CINDY MASTRY: In this clip, Faith is going to help me demonstrate how you can take the standing split bow variation of the standing split to an even more advance pose.
So using the blocks, that's going to help her be able to balance more easily and elevate the floor a little bit higher so it can take out any problems she might have with tight hamstrings or a tight low spine.
She's going to inhale and extend her arms up to the sky into a beautiful mountain pose.
Pressing into her feet, she's going to lengthen up and then fold forward.
Good.
Placing her hands on the block.
That's going to give her a little stability.
Good.
And then she's going to lengthen that leg up to the sky.
It doesn't have to come up very far.
It does not matter.
Good.
It's not about--it's not a competition.
She's going to bend her knee and bring her heel back in close to her body, giving her a really great, nice quad stretch.
Good.
She's going to engage her core and ground right through her foot, engage her glute and reach back and grab onto her foot.
Yes.
So she needs to focus and breathe, maybe even come through a little arch in the spine as she presses her hand right down into the earth and lengthens up with her foot.
And that's a beautiful, advance split bow variation.